fisher-price.com 2011-06-23

# Fisher-Price® Online Privacy Policy

### Fisher-Price® Online Privacy Policy

This is the online Privacy Policy of Fisher-Price, Inc. ("Fisher-Price"), a subsidiary of Mattel, Inc. ("Mattel"). Fisher-Price, Mattel, and all members of the Mattel family of companies are committed to protecting your online privacy when visiting a website operated by us. We do not collect and keep any personal information online from you unless you volunteer it and you are 18 or older. Please review the information below to familiarize yourself with our policies on website privacy, so that you can take full advantage of all the valuable information and fun activities available at our sites. The content on our sites may include information on our company and our products, parenting information, surveys, sweepstakes and contests, advertising, entertainment, and games, as well as opportunities to shop online, download music, or to submit, post, upload or display comments, suggestions, photos, videos and product ratings and reviews. We may also offer opportunities to apply for employment. Please note that that the computer network servers that make this site available may be located outside your country of residence. By using this site you agree to the transfer, collection processing and use of data by this site.

**A Special Note for Parents and Legal Guardians:**

It is Fisher-Price's intention to adhere to the requirements of the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 and the Children's Advertising Review Unit (CARU) guidelines in each of its websites directed to children.

While we make every effort to make your and your child's visit safe and enjoyable, we urge you to follow common sense when disclosing personal information on this site or any other site, and we encourage you to monitor your child's online use and to help us protect your child's privacy by instructing your child never to provide personal information on this site or any other without your permission.

YOUR USE OF THIS SITE SIGNIFIES YOUR ASSENT TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY, PLEASE DO NOT USE THIS SITE. Your use of this site is also subject to our website Terms and Conditions.

**  
1\. Does Fisher-Price collect any personal information about me?**

You don't have to register personal information with us in order to enjoy our website. However, some of our sites contain special sections and offer conveniences for visitors who do register personal information with us — for example, if you register a child's age, gender, your relationship to the child and your e-mail address, we'll send you content, promotional offers and product updates that are most relevant to your needs at the child's stage of development. We do not collect any personally identifiable information (such as names, addresses, and e-mail addresses) from you unless you are 18 or older and it is voluntarily provided — for instance, when registering for contests, sweepstakes, community areas, consumer insight panels, downloads, or free demos, completing our online customer surveys, registering for our e-mail newsletter, updates or other e-mail communications or purchasing products. The personal information that we ask for is usually first and last name, mailing address, telephone number and an e-mail address. We may also allow you to register for e-mail and other communications from third-party companies that might be of interest to you. See Question 3 for how we use this information. Remember, only people who are 18 or older may purchase products from our online store.

Most of our areas with content intended for children do not require a child to provide any personal information. We may ask that a child disclose personal information to participate in a game or other activity, but in such event, we do not require a child to disclose more information than is reasonably necessary to participate, and we do not register or keep this information in our database. For example, we may ask you to provide a child's first name in an activity so that a story can be personalized using the child's name, but the child's name is not registered or kept by us.

\- back to top -

**  
2\. What ordering information does Fisher-Price collect in our online store?**

The Fisher-Price Shop Online Store offers a selection of Fisher-Price products available for purchase online. Customers must be over age 18 with a valid credit card. When you place an order for product online from our online store, we collect information associated with the transaction. This information includes your name, mailing address, telephone number, e-mail address, shipping address, products ordered, and credit card information. We ask for this information so we can fulfill your order. When you place an online order, we will send a confirming e-mail message to the e-mail address you provide when placing the order. Any customer who prefers not to receive an online order confirmation may "opt-out" by indicating this preference on their order form.

While completing an online order, you have the option of registering certain information for use during future orders. If you choose to register, we will capture your login name, password, name and mailing address, alternate ship-to addresses, telephone number, e-mail address, and credit card information. You can access your online account information through the "My Account" feature at our website. When a registered visitor returns to the site to place subsequent orders, they can identify themselves with login name and password.

You may also have the option to include a child's date of birth and gender in your registration profile, and if included, this information will not be shared with outside third parties, but will be used by Fisher-Price and members of the Mattel family of companies to help us provide products and services that meet customer needs.

When a visitor places an order or registers on a site where transactions are handled by a third-party vendor, those transactions are conducted through the vendor's website. You should be sure to review the vendor's website terms and conditions and privacy policy before submitting any personal information or engaging in any transactions through any third-party website, as Fisher-Price is not responsible for any transactions made through third-party websites or for any content, terms and conditions, or privacy policies of such third-party websites.

\- back to top -

**  
3\. What does Fisher-Price do with the information we collect?**

We use the personal information we collect for the purposes indicated at the time you provide such information. For example, if you register in a contest, we will use the registration information to notify contest winners, or if you purchase a product, we will use the information to fulfill the order. If you place an order online, we add your name and address to our print catalog mailing list. With the permission of a visitor who is 18 years of age or over, personal information submitted in connection with a registration or other activity on our websites may be used for marketing and promotional purposes or shared with other Fisher-Price brands or members of the Mattel family of companies.

If you register for any of our e-mail newsletters, updates or other e-mail communications we offer, we will send the e-mail newsletters, updates and other communications requested by you. These communications will announce site upgrades, new product information, promotions and other updates that may be of interest to you. From time to time, we may send an e-mail asking if you'd like to participate in a survey. If you want to stop receiving these communications, you can access your account information through the "E-mail Updates" feature at our Site, contact us at 1-800-432-5437, or e-mail us at [fpconaff@fisher-price.com](mailto:fpconaff@fisher-price.com) to opt-out of receiving e-mail newsletters, updates or communications. Our e-mail communications instruct you how to "opt-out," so you can stop receiving our e-mails at any time. If you elect to register for e-mail or other communications from a third-party company, we will share the information you have provided with the applicable third party, and the third-party's use of such information will be subject to such third-party's privacy policy.

If you register to participate in a consumer insight panel, we will use your information and responses for internal business purposes and to improve our products, services and websites. In certain situations we may also use such personal information to contact you directly for the purpose of clarifying a response(s) to a survey or seeking additional responses or information. Our consumer insight panel e-mails and other communications instruct you how to "opt-out" of a consumer insight panel, so you can stop receiving consumer insight panel newsletters, surveys and e-mails at any time.

We may use non-personal information gathered online for internal marketing analysis and to improve our products, services and websites.

\- back to top -

**  
4\. Does Fisher-Price share information about me with others?**

We may give companies outside the Mattel family of companies access to our information databases but only if necessary to allow them to provide database or server maintenance or security, manage transactions, help us process and fulfill orders or requests, help us implement and facilitate surveys or consumer insight panels, or provide other similar services to Fisher-Price, such as technical or fulfillment services. Such disclosures are subject to non-disclosure commitments by third parties.

We occasionally share name and street address information from our print catalog mailing list with carefully selected companies whose offers you may be interested in. However, customers' telephone number(s), e-mail address(es) and credit card information are never shared. You may instruct us not to use your information at any time by e-mailing us at [fisher-pricestore@fisher-price.com](mailto:fisher-pricestore@fisher-price.com) or call 1-800-747-8697 or send the mailing label from the catalog to Fisher-Price-Inc., Attn: MOP Dept., P.O. Box 620978, Middleton, WI 53562-0978

If Fisher-Price believes that anyone's behavior on our sites may damage us or our sites or anyone else, we may disclose the relevant personal information in order to prevent this harm. In such a case, we might try to identify the wrongdoer, contact them or bring legal action against them. We may also disclose personal information if we believe that the disclosure is required by law, or in response to a legal request.

\- back to top -

**  
5\. How does Fisher-Price use "cookies" or collect other information automatically?**

Fisher-Price receives and stores certain information automatically whenever you visit our site. Examples of information we collect and analyze include the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet; computer and connection information such as browser type and version; the operating system and platform you use; and pages viewed and time spent on our site. This information helps us to optimize your experience at our sites. We also use cookies and clear GIFs, sometimes known as pixel tags or web beacons.

A "cookie" is a small file that we save on your computer's hard drive that contains non-personal information. Our cookies help to give you faster access to pages you have already visited, allow you to personalize your pages and us to customize our offerings, and help you to participate in some activities or events on the site. For instance, cookies keep track of items in your shopping cart and wish list. We also use cookies to help us determine how many people visit our sites, which of our web pages they use and how long they stay there. This information helps us evaluate our sites and which of our web features are a success and which might need improvement. You can disable the use of cookies through your Internet browser (like Internet Explorer or Netscape Navigator). Check your browser's Help menu to find out how to do so. However, if you disable cookies you may not be able to take advantage of some features of our sites.

We also use other technology, called clear GIFs, to provide us with other important anonymous information, such as when an e-mail has been opened. These tools help us understand features that interest our customers.

For administrative purposes, we also collect IP addresses, which are the automatic numbers assigned to your computer when you surf the web. Your IP address and cookies are not connected to any personally identifiable or online contact information like a name and address unless you place an order at our online store; however, if you place an order, all information we have about you will be associated with your customer file.

We use a third-party advertising technology to serve ads when you visit our website. This technology makes you anonymous to our ad-serving partner. In the course of delivering our advertisements to you, a unique third-party cookie may be placed or recognized on your browser. We also transmit site usage information about site visitors to the servers of a reputable third-party for the purpose of targeting our Internet banner advertisements on this site and other sites and to learn which ads bring users to our website. To do this, we use clear GIFs and cookies provided by our third-party ad server on this site. The information that is collected and logged on our behalf through this technology is not personally identifiable. For more information about our third-party ad server, or to learn your choices about not having this non-personal information used, please [click here](http://www.atlassolutions.com/privacy.aspx).

\- back to top -

**  
6\. How can I be removed from or update my contact information included in Fisher-Price's print catalog mailing list?**

If you do not wish to receive our catalogs, send the mailing label from your catalog to the following address, and we will remove your name from that list:

> > > Fisher-Price, Inc.   
> Attn: Mailing Changes   
> P.O. Box 620978   
> Middleton, WI 53562-0978

If you have recently moved or are planning to move in the near future, let us know of your change of address and we'll be sure to update our records. For all catalog mailing questions and changes, please call 1-800-747-8697, or send the information to Fisher-Price at the address shown above.

\- back to top -

**  
7\. How can I update my contact information or opt-out of Fisher-Price's database for e-mail communications?**

You always have the right to change your contact information in or be deleted from our e-mail database. You can access your account through the "E-Mail Updates" feature on our site to change your contact information, child information, or your newsletter, update or correspondence preferences. You can also follow the appropriate instructions at the bottom of any of our e-mail messages to you, call 1-800-432-5437, or e-mail us at [fpconaff@fisher-price.com](mailto:fpconaff@fisher-price.com) to change your contact information or to opt-out of receiving e-mail newsletters, updates or communications. Please remember that it may take time for our e-mail database to be updated.

\- back to top -

**  
8\. How can I opt-out of a Fisher-Price consumer insight panel?**

You always have the right to change your contact information in or be deleted from our consumer insight panel database. Follow the appropriate instructions at the bottom of any of our e-mail messages or other communications to you to change your contact information or to opt-out of receiving consumer insight panel e-mail newsletters, surveys or other communications. Please remember that it may take time for our consumer insight panel database to be updated.

\- back to top -

**  
9\. How does Fisher-Price safeguard personal information?**

We and our agents and affiliates use Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology to protect credit card data during transmission to our website, and adopt careful internal procedures to safeguard this information in our systems. We require our service providers and vendors to safeguard the privacy of any personal information they handle and to adhere to industry-accepted best practices to safeguard personal information. Users are warned, however, that no method is 100% secure. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially reasonable means to protect your information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. When you create a password and log-in name, we recommend that you adopt a unique name, combining letters and numbers that will be difficult for others to duplicate or guess. It is important for you to protect against unauthorized access to your password and to your computer. Be sure to sign off when finished, especially when using a shared computer.

\- back to top -

**  
10\. California Privacy Notice:**

Under California Law SB 27, California residents have the right to receive, once a year, information about third parties with whom we have shared information about you for their marketing purposes during the previous calendar year, and a description of the categories of personal information shared. To make such a request, please contact us at [fpconaff@fisher-price.com](mailto:fpconaff@fisher-price.com), including the phrase "California Privacy Request" in the subject line, and provide us with your name, address, and e-mail address. We will respond to you within 30 days of receiving such a request.

\- back to top -

**  
11\. Thanks for reading our Privacy Policy.**

We hope you have a better understanding of the activities and information offered on our sites and how we use information to improve our site, our products and services, to understand your needs, and to fulfill your requests. We may change our policy from time to time. When we do make changes, we will notify you of the new policy by posting it on our sites. By using our Site following the posting of changes to this Privacy Policy, you are deemed to consent to our then-current Privacy Policy.

If you have any questions, please do not hesitate to contact us!

> > > Fisher-Price, Inc.   
> 636 Girard Avenue   
> East Aurora, New York 14052   
> Telephone: 800-432-5437   
> fpconaff@Fisher-Price.com

\- back to top - © 2011 Mattel, Inc. All Rights Reserved.  
Updated April 7, 2009
